paycomonline.net 2019-02-06

# Paycom Privacy Policies

### Privacy Policy

Last modified: 4/25/2018

INTRODUCTION\- Paycom (“we”, “us”, or “our”) understands the need for transparency when it comes to the information we collect from visitors to and users of our website at [https://www.paycom.com](https://www.paycom.com/) (together with the mobile version of such site, and any related mobile applications, the “Website”). Accordingly, we have developed this Privacy Policy (this “policy”) to describe the types of information that we may collect from you, and our practices for collecting, using, maintaining, protecting and disclosing that information. 

Please read this policy carefully to understand how we treat the information we collect. If you do not agree with this policy, your choice is to cease immediately your use of our Website. By accessing or using this Website, you agree to this policy. We may update this policy from time to time (see Changes to Our Privacy Policy). Your continued use of this Website after we post any changes constitutes your acceptance of those changes, so please check the policy periodically for updates. 

INFORMATION WE COLLECT ABOUT YOU AND HOW WE COLLECT IT\- We collect personal information that you voluntarily provide to us, such as name, postal address, e-mail address, telephone number, place of business and any other information that could be used to personally identify you (collectively, “personal information”). You may voluntarily provide personal information when you fill in forms on our Website, reach out to us directly by sending us correspondence, or use the Website to place orders or enter into any other transactions with us. 

The Website and its servers may also collect other information from you, such as your industry, role in a business, and Human Resource needs, and technical information such as information regarding your internet connection, the hardware and software you use to access our Website, your IP address, page views, clicks, and other such information that does not personally identify you (collectively, “anonymous information”). 

AUTOMATIC DATA COLLECTION\- We may use cookies, web beacons, pixels, and similar technologies to automatically collect certain information about your online activities over time and across third-party websites or other online services. See Your Data Collection Choices for information on how you can opt out of and/or limit various tracking technologies. The technologies we use for this automatic data collection may include: 

  * _Cookies (or browser cookies)_. A cookie is a small file placed on the hard drive of your computer. You may refuse to accept browser cookies by activating the appropriate setting on your browser. However, if you select this setting you may be unable to access certain parts of our Website. Unless you have adjusted your browser setting so that it will refuse cookies, our system will issue cookies when you direct your browser to our Website. 
  * _Flash Cookies_. Certain features of our Website may use local stored objects (or Flash cookies) to collect and store information about your preferences and navigation to, from, and on our Website. Flash cookies are not managed by the same browser settings as are used for browser cookies. For information about managing your privacy and security settings for Flash cookies, see Your Data Collection Choices. 
  * _Web Beacons_. Pages of our the Website and our e-mails may contain small electronic files known as web beacons (also referred to as clear gifs, pixel tags, and single-pixel gifs) that permit us, for example, to count users who have visited those pages or opened an email and for other related Website statistics (for example, recording the popularity of certain Website content and verifying system and server integrity). 

We use information collected by the technologies described above, to help us improve our Website and to deliver a better and more personalized service, including by enabling us to: 

  * Estimate our audience size and usage patterns. 
  * Store information about your preferences, allowing us to customize our Website to your specific business needs. 
  * Speed up your searches. 
  * Recognize you when you return to our Website. 

Some content or applications on the Website are served by third-parties, including advertisers, ad networks and servers, content providers, and application providers. These third parties may use cookies alone or in conjunction with web beacons or other tracking technologies to collect information about you when you use our Website. The information they collect may be associated with your personal information or they may collect information, including personal information, about your online activities over time and across different websites and other online services. They may use this information to provide you with interest-based advertising or other targeted content. We do not control these third parties’ tracking technologies or how they may be used. If you have any questions about an advertisement, or other targeted content, you should contact the responsible provider directly. For information about how you can opt out of receiving targeted advertising from many providers, see Your Data Collection Choices. 

HOW WE USE YOUR INFORMATION\- We may use personal information: 

  * To fulfill the purpose for which you provide it (for example to provide products, services, support, or information you request, to review your job application through our Careers page, or to respond to your correspondence or other requests); 
  * to carry out our obligations and enforce our rights arising from any contracts entered into between you and us, including for billing and collection; 
  * to contact you regarding any transactions you’ve entered into with us; 
  * to notify you about changes to our Website or any products or services we offer or provide through it; or 
  * in any other way we may describe when you provide the information, or for which you provide consent. 

We may also use your information to market, advertise, promote or otherwise contact you about our products and services. If you do not want us to use your information in this way, see Your Data Collection Choices for instructions on how to opt out of these communications. We may use anonymous information, which does not identify you personally, in any way we deem appropriate. 

DISCLOSURE OF YOUR INFORMATION\- We may disclose personal information: 

  * To our subsidiaries and affiliates; 
  * to contractors, service providers, and other third parties who support our business operations (e.g., payment processors, sales or support representatives, hosting providers, marketing partners, and other business consultants) who are bound by contractual obligations to keep personal information confidential and use it only for the purposes for which we disclose it to them; 
  * to a buyer or other successor in the event of a merger, divestiture, restructuring, reorganization, dissolution, or other sale or transfer of some or all of our assets, whether as a going concern or as part of bankruptcy, liquidation, or similar proceeding, in which personal information held by us is among the assets transferred; 
  * any other entity disclosed by us when you provide the information, or for which you provide consent; or 
  * to comply with any court order, law, or legal process, including to respond to any government or regulatory request, to enforce or apply our website policies and other agreements, for billing and collection purposes, or if we believe disclosure is necessary or appropriate to protect our rights, property, or safety or that of our customers or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organizations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction. 

YOUR DATA COLLECTION CHOICES\- We strive to provide you with choices regarding the personal information you provide to us. We have created mechanisms to provide you with the following control over your information: 

  * _Tracking Technologies_. You can set your browser to refuse all or some browser cookies, or to alert you when cookies are being sent. To learn how you can manage your Flash cookie settings, visit the Flash player settings page on Adobe’s [website](https://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager07.html). If you disable or refuse cookies, please note that some parts of this site may then be inaccessible or not function properly. 
  * _Location_. Mobile applications may collect real-time information about the location of your device for geo-fencing, mileage tracking or similar purposes. If you do not want us to collect this information, you may decline our request or disable location services in your mobile device’s settings. However, opting out of the collection of location information will cause location-based features to be disabled and the online and/or mobile application may not function properly. We may also offer clients an option to use your approximate clock-in location based off an IP address. You may also opt out of this method via the application’s settings, however, opting out will interfere with the application’s functionality. 
  * _Stored Information and Files_. Our mobile application also may access metadata and other information associated with other files stored on your device. This may include, for example, photographs, audio and video clips, personal contacts, and address book information. You may opt out of this data collection in your mobile device’s settings, however, opting out will interfere with the application’s functionality. 
  * _Your Information and Third-Party Advertising_. We do not control third parties’ collection or use of your information to serve interest-based advertising. However, these third parties may provide you with ways to choose not to have your information collected or used in this way. You can opt out of receiving targeted ads from members of the Network Advertising Initiative (“NAI”) [https://optout.networkadvertising.org](https://optout.networkadvertising.org/) on the NAI’s website. You can opt out of receiving interest-based advertising from members of the Digital Advertising Alliance by utilizing their consumer choice tool at [https://optout.aboutads.info](https://optout.aboutads.info/). You can also opt-out by adjusting your internet and/or mobile browser preferences. 
  * _Promotional Offers from Paycom_. If you do not wish to have your email address or other contact information used by Paycom to promote our own or third parties’ products or services, you can opt-out at any other time by sending us an email stating your request to [privacy@paycom.com](mailto:privacy@paycom.com "email privacy@paycom.com"). If we have sent you a promotional email, you may opt out using the unsubscribe or opt-out link in the email, if applicable, or by sending us a return email asking to be omitted from future email distributions. This opt out does not apply to information provided to Paycom as a result of a product or service purchase, product service experience or other transactions. 
  * _Do Not Track Signals_. The Website currently does not recognize or respond to browser “do not track” signals. 
  * _Twitter_. One of the third parties we may use for advertising purposes, is Twitter, Inc. Information about how Twitter uses data and how you may choose what information is collected may be found at <https://support.twitter.com/articles/20170405#>
  * _Google Analytics_. One of the third party services we use for advertising purposes is Google Analytics. Information about how Google Analytics uses data can be found at [www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/). 
  * _YouTube API Services_. One of the third party services we use for audiovisual content viewing is the YouTube API Services. Information about the YouTube API Services can be found at <https://developers.google.com/youtube/terms/api-services-terms-of-service>. By using the features of the Website utilizing the YouTube API Services, you agree to be bound by the YouTube Terms of Service, found at <https://www.youtube.com/t/terms>. 

If you would like to access or correct your personal information, you may do so by visiting your account profile (if you have one) or by contacting us at [privacy@paycom.com](mailto:privacy@paycom.com "email privacy@paycom.com"). 

CHILDREN UNDER THE AGE OF 13\- Our Website is not intended for children under 13 years of age. We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under 13. If you are under 13, do not use or provide any information on this Website or on or through any of its features/register on the Website, make any purchases through the Website, use any of the interactive or public comment features of this Website or provide any information about yourself to us, including your name, address, telephone number, email address, or any screen name or user name you may use. If we learn we have collected or received personal information from a child under 13, we will promptly take commercially reasonable steps to delete that information. If you believe we might have any information from or about a child under 13, please contact us at [privacy@paycom.com](mailto:privacy@paycom.com "email privacy@paycom.com"). 

YOUR CALIFORNIA PRIVACY RIGHTS\- - California Civil Code Section § 1798.83 permits Website users that are California residents to request certain information regarding the disclosure of personal information to third parties for direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please send an email to [privacy@paycom.com](mailto:privacy@paycom.com "email privacy@paycom.com"). 

DATA SECURITY\- We have implemented at least industry standard measures designed to secure your personal information from accidental loss and from unauthorized access, use, alteration, and disclosure. The safety and security of your information also depends on you. You are responsible for keeping your username, password, and any other login credentials or user verification information confidential. You may not share this information with anyone. Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure, so we cannot guarantee the security of your personal information transmitted to our Website. Any transmission of personal information is at your own risk. We are not responsible for circumvention of any privacy settings or security measures contained on the Website. 

In order to protect you and your data and that of our other users, we may suspend your access to the Website without notice, pending an investigation, if any breach of security is suspected. 

For more information on our IT security practices, [click here](https://paycom.com/PDF/SecurityStandards.pdf). 

CHANGES TO OUR PRIVACY POLICY\- For any changes we make to this policy, including making material changes to how we treat our users’ personal information, we will post an updated policy on this page, along with a notice that the privacy policy has been updated on the Website home page. The date the privacy policy was last revised is identified at the top of the page. Please be aware, you are responsible for inspecting our website to make yourself up-to-date with our privacy policy. 

CLIENT DATA\- We receive personal information from or on behalf of our clients (employers) and their personnel regarding their personnel and their personnel’s dependents and family members. Such information is required for us to effectively provide our services to our clients, and may include social security numbers, payroll information, tax information, biometric information (such as retina or iris scans, fingerprint scans, voiceprints scans of hand or face geometry, or other similar biometric identifiers), and other information our clients may provide in order for us to perform our services (collectively, “client data”). Client data is subject to the same conditions as personal information under this policy, except as further specified in this “Client Data” section of this policy. We use at least industry standard security policies and measures to help prevent any unauthorized access to client data. 

We process, use, and share client data as instructed or permitted by the applicable client. We may transmit client data over international borders as necessary for providing our services in accordance with our standard business practices and this policy, but we will maintain reasonable security policies regardless of where client data is stored or processed. 

We will share any client data with the client and any third parties as instructed or permitted by the client. We may also share client data with other third party data processors who facilitate our provision of the services requested by the client and who are prohibited from using client data except for such purpose. We may also be required to share client data with applicable government entities (for example, the IRS, state unemployment agencies, state income agencies, workers compensation auditors, 401k administrators and entities who participate in the NACHA program for funds transfer purposes) or as otherwise required by law. 

Our clients may transmit their personnel’s biometric information to Paycom. Biometric information is stored while a client's personnel are active within the Paycom system. Biometric information not tied to our clients' personnel or tied to our clients' personnel that are inactive within our system are permanently deleted from our servers on a nightly basis. Absent a valid warrant or subpoena issued by a court of competent jurisdiction, Paycom’s retention and destruction standards for fingerscan templates will be followed. 

If you are one of our clients’ personnel, or the dependent or family member of one of our clients’ personnel, and you have any questions or concerns regarding your personal information or your privacy rights, or you would like to access or correct your personal information, please contact your employer. 

CONTACT INFORMATION\- To ask questions or comment about this privacy policy and our privacy practices, contact us at: [privacy@paycom.com](mailto:privacy@paycom.com "email privacy@paycom.com").
